<form>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.hideidentity</id>
        <label>Hide Identity</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If enabled, id.server and hostname.bind queries are refused.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.hideversion</id>
        <label>Hide Version</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If enabled, version.server and version.bind queries are refused.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.prefetch</id>
        <label>Prefetch Support</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            Message cache elements are prefetched before they expire to help keep the cache up to date.
            When enabled, this option can cause an increase of around 10% more DNS traffic and load
            on the server, but frequently requested items will not expire from the cache.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.prefetchkey</id>
        <label>Prefetch DNS Key Support</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            DNSKEYs are fetched earlier in the validation process when a Delegation signer is encountered.
            This helps lower the latency of requests but does utilize a little more CPU.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.dnssecstripped</id>
        <label>Harden DNSSEC Data</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            DNSSEC data is required for trust-anchored zones. If such data is absent, the zone becomes bogus.
            If this is disabled and no DNSSEC data is received, then the zone is made insecure.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.serveexpired</id>
        <label>Serve Expired Responses</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            Serve expired responses from the cache with a TTL of 0 without waiting for the actual resolution to finish.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.qnameminstrict</id>
        <label>Strict QNAME Minimisation</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            Send minimum amount of information to upstream servers to enhance privacy.
            Do not fall-back to sending full QNAME to potentially broken nameservers.
            A lot of domains will not be resolvable when this option in enabled.
            Only use if you know what you are doing.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.extendedstatistics</id>
        <label>Extended Statistics</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If enabled, extended statistics are printed.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.logqueries</id>
        <label>Log Queries</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            If enabled, prints one line per query to the log, with the log timestamp and IP address, name, type and class.
            Note that it takes time to print these lines, which makes the server (significantly) slower. Odd
            (nonprintable) characters in names are printed as '?'.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.logreplies</id>
        <label>Log Replies</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            If enabled, prints one line per reply to the log, with the log timestamp and IP address, name, type,
            class, return code, time to resolve, whether the reply is from the cache and the response size.
            Note that it takes time to print these lines, which makes the server (significantly) slower. Odd
            (nonprintable) characters in names are printed as '?'.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.logtagqueryreply</id>
        <label>Tag Queries and Replies</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            If enabled, prints the word 'query: ' and 'reply: ' with logged queries and replies. This makes filtering
            logs easier.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.logverbosity</id>
        <label>Log Level Verbosity</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            Select the log verbosity. Level 0 means no verbosity, only errors. Level 1 gives operational information.
            Level 2 gives detailed operational information. Level 3 gives query level information, output per query.
            Level 4 gives algorithm level information. Level 5 logs client identification for cache misses.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.msgcachesize</id>
        <label>Message Cache Size</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            Size of the message cache. The message cache stores DNS rcodes and validation statuses.
            The RRSet cache will automatically be set to twice this amount. The RRSet cache contains the actual RR data.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.outgoingnumtcp</id>
        <label>Outgoing TCP Buffers</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            The number of outgoing TCP buffers to allocate per thread.
            If 0 is selected then no TCP queries, to authoritative servers, are done.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.incomingnumtcp</id>
        <label>Incoming TCP Buffers</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            The number of incoming TCP buffers to allocate per thread.
            If 0 is selected then no TCP queries, from clients, are accepted.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.numqueriesperthread</id>
        <label>Number of queries per thread</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            The number of queries that every thread will service simultaneously. If more queries arrive that
            need to be serviced, and no queries can be jostled, then these queries are dropped.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.jostletimeout</id>
        <label>Jostle Timeout</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            This timeout is used for when the server is very busy. This protects against denial of service by
            slow queries or high query rates.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.cachemaxttl</id>
        <label>Maximum TTL for RRsets and messages</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>
            Configure a maximum Time to live for RRsets and messages in the cache.
            The default is 86400 seconds (1 day). When the internal TTL expires the cache item is expired.
            This can be configured to force the resolver to query for data more often and
            not trust (very large) TTL values.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.cacheminttl</id>
        <label>Minimum TTL for RRsets and messages</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>
            Configure a minimum Time to live for RRsets and messages in the cache.
            The default is 0 seconds. If the minimum value kicks in, the data is cached for longer than
            the domain owner intended, and thus less queries are made to look up the data.
            The 0 value ensures the data in the cache is as the domain owner intended.
            High values can lead to trouble as the data in the cache might not match up with the actual data anymore.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.infrahostttl</id>
        <label>TTL for Host Cache entries</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            Time to live for entries in the host cache. The host cache contains roundtrip timing and EDNS
            support information.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.infracachenumhosts</id>
        <label>Number of Hosts to cache</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            Number of hosts for which information is cached.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.advanced.unwantedreplythreshold</id>
        <label>Unwanted Reply Threshold</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            If enabled, a total number of unwanted replies is kept track of in every thread.
            When it reaches the threshold, a defensive action is taken and a warning is printed to the log file.
            This defensive action is to clear the RRSet and message caches, hopefully flushing away any poison.
            The default is disabled, but if enabled a value of 10 million is suggested.
        </help>
    </field>
</form>
