<form>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.enabled</id>
        <label>Enable Unbound</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.port</id>
        <label>Listen Port</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>The TCP/UDP port used for responding to DNS queries.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.active_interface</id>
        <label>Network Interfaces</label>
        <type>select_multiple</type>
        <help>
            Interface IP addresses used for responding to queries from clients.
            If an interface has both IPv4 and IPv6 IPs, both are used.
            Queries to other interface IPs not selected below are discarded.
            The default behavior is to respond to queries on every available IPv4 and IPv6 address.
        </help>
        <hint>All (recommended)</hint>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.dnssec</id>
        <label>Enable DNSSEC Support</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.dns64</id>
        <label>Enable DNS64 Support</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If this option is set, Unbound will synthesize AAAA records from A records if no actual AAAA records are present.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.dns64prefix</id>
        <label>DNS64 Prefix</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <hint>64:ff9b::/96</hint>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.noarecords</id>
        <label>Enable AAAA-only mode</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If this option is set, Unbound will remove all A records from the answer section of all responses.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.regdhcp</id>
        <label>Register ISC DHCP4 Leases</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If this option is set, then machines that specify their hostname when requesting a DHCP lease will be registered in Unbound, so that their name can be resolved.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.regdhcpdomain</id>
        <label>DHCP Domain Override</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>The default domain name to use for DHCP lease registration. If empty, the system domain is used.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.regdhcpstatic</id>
        <label>Register DHCP Static Mappings</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            <![CDATA[If this option is set, then DHCP static mappings will be registered in Unbound, so that their name can be resolved.
            You should also set the domain in <a href="/system_general.php">System: Settings: General</a> to the proper value.]]>
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.noreglladdr6</id>
        <label>Do not register IPv6 Link-Local addresses</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            If this option is set, then IPv6 link-local addresses will not be registered in Unbound,
            preventing return of unreachable address when more than one listen interface is configured.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.noregrecords</id>
        <label>Do not register system A/AAAA records</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            <![CDATA[If this option is set, then no A/AAAA records for the configured listen interfaces will be generated.
            If desired, you can manually add them in
            <a href="/ui/unbound/overrides">Unbound DNS: Overrides</a>.
            Use this to control which interface IP addresses are mapped to the system host/domain name
            as well as to restrict the amount of information exposed in replies to queries for the system host/domain name.]]>
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.txtsupport</id>
        <label>TXT Comment Support</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>If this option is set, then any descriptions associated with Host entries and DHCP Static mappings will create a corresponding TXT record.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.cacheflush</id>
        <label>Flush DNS Cache during reload</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>
            If this option is set, the DNS cache will be flushed during each daemon reload.
            This is the default behavior for Unbound, but may be undesired when multiple dynamic interfaces require frequent reloading.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.safesearch</id>
        <label>Force SafeSearch</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <style>safesearch</style>
        <help>Force the usage of SafeSearch on Google, DuckDuckGo, Bing, Qwant, PixaBay and YouTube</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.local_zone_type</id>
        <label>Local Zone Type</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            <![CDATA[The local zone type used for the system domain.
            Type descriptions are available under "local-zone:" in the
            <a href="https://nlnetlabs.nl/documentation/unbound/unbound.conf/#local-zone">unbound.conf(5)</a> manual page. The default is 'transparent'.]]>
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.outgoing_interface</id>
        <label>Outgoing Network Interfaces</label>
        <type>select_multiple</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <hint>All (recommended)</hint>
        <help>
            Utilize different network interfaces that Unbound will use to send queries to authoritative servers and receive their replies.
            By default all interfaces are used. Note that setting explicit outgoing interfaces only works when they are statically configured.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>unbound.general.enable_wpad</id>
        <label>WPAD Records</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <advanced>true</advanced>
        <help>
            If this option is set, CNAME records for the WPAD host of all configured domains will be automatically added
            as well as overrides for TXT records for domains. This allows automatic proxy configuration in your network
            but you should not enable it if you are not using WPAD or if you want to configure it by yourself.
        </help>
    </field>
</form>
