<form>
    <field>
        <type>header</type>
        <label>General Settings</label>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.disablepreempt</id>
        <label>Disable preempt</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>When this device is configured as CARP master it will try to switch to master when powering up, this option will keep this one slave if there already is a master on the network. A reboot is required to take effect.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.disconnectppps</id>
        <label>Disconnect dialup interfaces</label>
        <type>checkbox</type>
        <help>When this device is configured as CARP backup it will disconnect all PPP type interfaces and try to reconnect them when becoming master again.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.pfsyncinterface</id>
        <label>Synchronize all states via</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>This enables state insertion, update, and deletion messages between firewalls by utilizing the selected interface for communication. Best choose a dedicated interface for this type of communication to prevent manipulation of states causing security issues.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.pfsyncversion</id>
        <label>Sync compatibility</label>
        <type>dropdown</type>
        <help>
            Newer versions of OPNsense offer additional attributes in the state synchronization, for compatibility reasons you can optionally choose an older version here.
            Always make sure both nodes use the same version to avoid inconsistent state tables.
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.pfsyncpeerip</id>
        <label>Synchronize Peer IP</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <hint>224.0.0.240</hint>
        <help>Setting this option will force pfsync to synchronize its state table to this IP address. The default is directed multicast.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <type>header</type>
        <label><![CDATA[Configuration Synchronization Settings (XMLRPC Sync) <a href="/status_habackup.php">Perform synchronization </a>]]></label>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.synchronizetoip</id>
        <label>Synchronize Config</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>
            Enter the IP address of the firewall to which the selected configuration sections should be synchronized.
            This should be empty on the backup machine. When an IP address is offered, both web GUI configurations should be equal (port and protocol).
        </help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.username</id>
        <label>Remote System Username</label>
        <type>text</type>
        <help>Enter the web GUI username of the system entered above for synchronizing your configuration.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.password</id>
        <label>Remote System Password</label>
        <type>password</type>
        <help>Enter the web GUI password of the system entered above for synchronizing your configuration.</help>
    </field>
    <field>
        <type>header</type>
        <label>Services to synchronize (XMLRPC Sync)</label>
    </field>
    <field>
        <id>hasync.syncitems</id>
        <label>Services</label>
        <type>select_multiple</type>
        <help>Select the services that should be send to the other host.</help>
    </field>
</form>
